# Hasan G. Jaffal

# **Project Manager and Senior ICT Professional**

Beirut, Lebanon - 00961 3 926130 - jaftalks@icloud.com - jaftalks.com

#### **PROFILE**

Result oriented Senior ICT professional with 10+ years of experience and consistent track record of successfully managing & delivering small and large scale projects in the private, public and non-profit sectors and have worked on international software projects across a range of industries in Africa and the middle east.

Project Management – PMP – Agile Scrum – Business Analysis – Requirements Management - Software, Web and Mobile Development, ICT for Development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### ArabiaGIS, Lebanon

### **Head of Project Office / Project Manager**

2012-Present [5 years]

Head of Project Management Office at ArabiaGIS, my duties start from the inception phase, to the budgeting, planning, controlling and the delivery phase. My core role functions are:

- Managing medium to large scale international software projects.
- Deliver high-profile projects within expedited time frames while meeting all business deliverables.
- Prioritize, allocate, and follow up on tasks to project resources
- Prepare software concepts, pitch solutions and respond to RFPs.
- Engage with customers to analyze and collect user, business, and, system requirements.
- Prepare and Present analysis, and training documentation.
- Providing consultancy in Software Architecture and Design and Coding best practices.

### **Senior Software Developer and Solution Architect**

2008-2012 [4 years]

Working as Software Architect, Developer and Project Leader, I was mainly responsible of the following tasks:

- To schedule, lead, achieve and follow up projects.
- To perform business, functional and technical analysis and writing technical documentation.
- To develop WPF, Silverlight, Web, Mobile and GIS applications.
- To design software solutions and select technologies and design patterns.

### Sokin (Ashour Group), Congo

## **Software Developer**

2006-2008 [2 years]

Working as enterprise applications developer at Sokin:

- Develop web and desktop applications
- Perform requirements analysis and documentation
- Participate in System Designs and documentation

### **EDUCATION**

2006 Lebanese University - BS in Computer Sciences

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- 2012 Certified Project Management Professional, PMP
- 2011 Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Arabia

#### VOLUNTEERING

# 2013 2017 talentmethods.org

Founded <u>talentmethods.org</u> which is an initiative that aims to empower Non-Profit organizations with tools to build online presence and to make use of data to make better decisions using latest open source technologies.

#### 2014 2017 Project Management Institute: PMI Lebanon

Elected Board Member and Director of Administration.

- Responsible of the Board Administration
- Project Manager of the new website Development
- Member of the Digital Media Marketing Committee

## 2016 Project Management Institute: PMI Lebanon

Project Manager Volunteer of the 3-years Business Plan development project. Conducted several researches, interviews and workshop to come up, along with the NGO board of directors, with a 3 years business plan.

# 2016 2017 **Nahnoo - Lebanon (2 Months)**

ICT for Development volunteer helping in developing website site structure and coordinating with developers. And providing consultancy on ICT solutions

## 2016 2017 **Green Southerners - Lebanon (3 Months)**

ICT for Development volunteer helping developing online presence and mapping environmental violations using <u>tahaki.com</u> and Mobile App.

# 2016 American University of Beirut: Lebanon

Jury Member of the Business Project Management Graduation Projects

# 2016 Hagazian University: Lebanon

Jury Member of the Business Project Management Graduation Projects

## CONFERENCES

2016	Attended the Agile Tour 2016 Conference, Beirut
2016	Attended the World Humanitarian Summit, Istanbul
2016	Attended the PMI Leadership Institute Conference, Barcelona
2015	Attended the PMI Regional Leadership Meeting, Dubai
2015	Attended the Talent Management Conference, Online
2015	Attended the Organizational Agility Conference, Online
2015	Organized the Second National Project Management Conference, Beirut
2015	Speaker at the Agile Tour, Beirut
2014	Speaker about Agile Scrum at AUB, Beirut
2013	Attended ESRI User Conference, Dubai

2012 Attended the First National Project Management Conference, Beirut

2012 Attended ESRI User Conference, Beirut